And so I think it makes sense for us to look for ways to mitigate that impact. And we need to do research to do that. We need to understand the science behind that. I've noticed that there's a theme that's kind of developed at TED, which is kind of, "fear versus hope," or "creativity versus caution." And of course, we need both of those. So there aren't any silver bullets. This is certainly not a silver bullet. But we need science to tell us what our options are; that informs both our creativity and our caution. So I am an optimist about our future selves, but I'm not an optimist because I think our problems are small. I'm an optimist because I think our capacity to deal with our problems is much greater than we imagine. Thank you very much. (Applause) This talk sparked a lot of controversy at TED2017, and we encourage you to look at discussions online to see other points of view.
Y por eso creo que tiene sentido que busquemos maneras de mitigar ese impacto. Y necesitamos investigaciones para lograrlo. Necesitamos entender la ciencia que hay detrás. Me he percatado de que hay un tema que se desarrolla en TED, "el miedo contra la esperanza", o "la creatividad contra la precaución". Y claro, necesitamos de todo ello. Así que no hay soluciones mágicas. Ciertamente esta no lo es. Pero necesitamos que la ciencia nos dé opciones, que impacten en nuestra creatividad y precaución. Soy optimista respecto a nuestro futuro. No es que sea optimista porque nuestros problemas sean pequeños sino porque creo que nuestra capacidad para lidiar con nuestros problemas es mucho más grande de lo que imaginamos. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos) Esta charla desató mucha controversia en TED2017, los invitamos a leer otras opiniones en línea.